《越狱》前情提要K
Previously on Prison Break:
他不会有事的，我向你保证
It will work out. You have my word.
小心一点
Be careful.
珍会照顾你的
Jane's gonna look after you. Hey.
我有个妹妹，我们15年没说过话
I have a sister I haven't talked to in 15 years.
-她会因此过得比较好吗？ -布鲁斯？
- You think she's better off for it? - Bruce?
虽然说好不打这号码 但我要知道你是否平安
We said not to use this number, but I needed to know you were okay.
是你
It was you.
你在说什么，莎拉？
What are you talking about, Sara?
-我有三个字要说，我们跑 -嗯
I got three words for you. We gotta run.
我要自首，但我有一个条件
I wanna turn myself in. But I got one condition.
你的妻子一小时前已经出狱
Your wife was released an hour ago.
她很快就会赶来 你要遵守你的承诺
She'll be here soon. Just hold up your end of the deal.
我会帮你抓到斯科菲尔德
I'll get you scofield.
一个赞同我们目标的 国家安全局分析师
An NsA analyst sympathetic to our cause...
他发现总统 和戴伦斯史泰门的通话
...got his hands on a phone conversation the president had with Terrence steadman...
就在你据称谋杀他的两周后
...two weeks after you supposedly killed him.
24小时后，丹奎迪死了 分析师下落不明
Twenty-four hours later, Tancredi is dead, the analyst is missing...
而梯队系统上的白宫录音 已从主要资料库被删除
...and the White House echelon tapes have been deleted from the mainframe.
有段录音可以当成铁证
There's a tape. It gives us everything we need.
如果找到 林克就能重获自由
Linc will be set free if we find it.
你手上的证据很重要
You have something here.
很多人会希望你没有这个证据 但已经在你手上了
There'll be a lot who wish you didn't, but you do.
你觉得是对话内容吗？
You think it's a conversation?
是不可告人的内容
One they don't want us to hear.
-准备好了吗？ -放吧
- You ready? - Let's do it.
老天爷
Oh, my God.
没错
Yeah.
帕托西克，死了
Patoshik, dead.
富兰克林，遭监禁 并协助追捕斯科菲尔德和柏劳
Franklin, incarcerated and assisting with the capture of scofield and Burrows.
-这方法是照什么程序办的？ -我会处理
- What exactly is the protocol with that? - I'll handle that.
各位，已经成功一半了
We're at the halfway mark, people.
柏劳、斯科菲尔德 包威、苏克
Burrows, scofield, Bagwell, sucre.
他们依然在逃
They're still out there.
-听说有消息来自K -墨西哥
- Now, I heard a report came in from... - Mexico.
费南多苏克 在伊斯塔帕机场差点被逮捕
Fernando sucre was almost apprehended at the airport in lxtapa.
失陪了
Excuse me.
请到我的办公室
My office, please.
（亚历山大曼宏 特别探员）
-你跑来这里做什么？ -我来拿我的钱
- What the hell are you doing here? - I came for my damn money.
-你的什么？ -帕托西克一事的奖赏
- Your what? - The Patoshik reward money.
奖赏意味着 有人会拿到钱当奖赏
See, how a reward works is, someone gets rewarded the money.
既然疯仔是我找到的
And since I'm the one who bloodhounded Haywire...
赏金就应该给我
...the money gets rewarded to me.
你跑到我办公室K？
You come to my office...?
如果你肯回我一通电话 我也不必跑来
If you'd returned any of my calls, I wouldn't have had to.
-我们谈好条件了 -条件是你低调行事
- We had a deal. - The deal was you stay under the radar.
这叫低调吗，布拉德？
Is this under the radar, Brad?
不，这里满是联邦探员 现在他们全都见过你了
No, this is an office full of federal agents who now have all seen your face.
他们看到什么我不在乎
Hey, I don't care what they see.
管你的，如果你不付钱 我就出去露屁股
Hell, if you don't pay up, I'll go out there and drop trou.
帕托西克死了，你这蠢蛋
Patoshik died, you stupid son of a bitch.
有文件要呈报，你当然会拿到钱
There's paperwork involved. Of course, you're gonna get the money.
但你要耐心一点
But you'll have to be patient.
如果你敢 再跑来我的办公室
And if you ever come in my office again...
你不只别想见到钱
...you will not only never see the cash...
连太阳都别想看到了
...you'll never see another sunrise.
赏金已经是你的了 你想继续吵着要钱
Now, we gonna keep crying about money you've already got coming to you...
还是想多赚一点？
...or do you wanna make some more?
你说吧
I'm listening.
去过墨西哥吗？
Ever been to Mexico?
如果把录音交给媒体 政府会不承认
We give this to the press, the government will discredit it.
就像我们拍的影带一样
Just like they did with the tape we made.
好吧
Okay.
那我们该怎么做？
So, what do we do with it?
爸说他在政府里还有照应的人
There are people in the administration Dad was working with.
如果交给他们 他们就有如山的铁证
If we give it to them, they'll finally have the smoking gun they need...
能搞垮卡洛琳雷诺兹
...to bring Caroline Reynolds down.
由他们把录音公诸于世 不能由我们来
But they'll release the tape, not us.
她无法和自己任命的人撇清关系
And how can she discredit her own appointees? Sure.
我们要把唯一 能赦免我的证据
We're gonna give the only thing that can exonerate me...
交给政府的人？
...to someone who works for the government?
同一个陷害我的政府？
The same government that set me up?!
我们得找到信得过的人 一个正直的人
We'll have to find someone we can trust. Someone honest.
珍菲力普
Jane Phillips.
她会知道谁可以帮助我们
She'll know someone that can help us.
她和爸合作过 现在正在照顾罗杰
She worked with Dad. She's watching L.J.
我信任她，迈克
I trust her, Michael.
她可以帮忙找人
She'll do it. She'll find someone.
希望你的直觉没错
Well, I hope you're right.
因为这是我们最后的希望
Because this is our last shot.
这把一定合适
This'll do you right.
射程达一千码
It's good from a thousand yards out.
目标准吗？
She a clean shot?
就像好女人一样，不偏不倚
Like a good woman, she does not stray.
不锈钢沟槽外管 口径点308
Bariment stainless steel fluted barrel, .308 caliber...
子弹重175喱，中空型弹头
...175 grain, hollow point.
-枪箱我也要 -它是拼凑枪
- I'll take the case too. - She's a throw-in.
枪枝序号已经磨平了
The serial numbers have been cleaned.
弹膛也被刮过 好混淆弹道的调查
The chamber's been scraped to throw off ballistics...
以防你不是要射铁罐子的话
...just in case you're not, you know, shooting at tin cans.
不，我的猎物大多了
No, I'm hunting bigger game than that.
等等K
Hey! Hey, hey!
片名：越狱风云
剧名：回到原点
没有回应
Radio silence.
（需要帮忙，我女儿病了 百元钞票）
我不知道他多久会上来看一次 好吗？
I just don't know how often he checks this thing, all right?
看来不常来 因为你已经留言三次了
Well, it seems not that often, considering you've posted three messages.
我开始怀疑我为何需要你了
I'm starting to wonder why I need you at all.
为了抓到斯科菲尔德 不然我们在干嘛？
To get scofield. What? What are we doing here?
我也可以打字 是斯科菲尔德看不见留言的是谁
Well, I can type, and scofield can't see who's sending him the messages.
但他看得出你们这些 三流探员的计谋
Well, he's gonna see whatever little rent-a-fed cops that you guys have set up...
拆穿你们设下 与他见面的陷阱
...whatever place you'll set up to meet him.
你和我都清楚这小子有多聪明
You and I both know how smart this kid is, right?
显然比你聪明 现在穿囚衣的人是你
Smarter than you, considering you're wearing orange.
-是吗？ -对
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
新来的绝对不会从藏匿处现身
Fish is not gonna peek his little white ass out from any rock that he's hiding...
除非他看见K
...unless he sees a...
熟人K你指的是你？
A familiar... And that's your face?
对，那当然 别装作你不需要我
Yeah, you're damned straight it is. Don't pretend like you don't need me.
你说你偷听到 他告诉苏克网站的事
You said you overheard him telling sucre about a website...
-别装作你不需要我 -你只是偷听到K
- Don't pretend you don't need me! - You overheard...
-他是烂好人 -我看不出这有何帮助
- He's a Boy scout. - I don't see how that helps!
如果你有点耐心，他就会回应我
If you have a bit of patience, he will hit me back!
现在只有我在帮助你家人
I'm the only one now helping your family.
-是我在帮好吗？ -我也有
- I help my family, okay? - So do I.
我让凯西出狱，让蒂蒂接受治疗
I got Kacee released. I get Dede medical care.
我让你和她们见面 我也有权利收回这些特权
I'm the one that allows you to visit them, and I'm the one that can take it away.
你很清楚我们需要彼此，对吧？
It looks like we both need each other, doesn't it?
-真的吗？ -我会遵守我的诺言
- Do we? - So I'll hold up my end of the bargain.
你猜怎着？你也要遵守诺言
And guess what? You hold up yours.
所以不要再烦我了
Now, get off my back.
只要你交出我要的 你就能达成愿望
You can get what you want. Just give me what I want.
把斯科菲尔德引出来
Give me scofield.
（华盛顿州，普尔曼）
-你好？ -你好，小子
- Hello? - Hey, buddy,
爸？
Dad?
对，是我，你好吗？
Yeah, it's me. How you holding up?
还好，你呢？
Okay. How about you?
很好K
Good. Good.
我想你
I miss you.
我也是
Yeah, me too,
我不知道你有珍的号码
I didn't know you had Jane's number.
对，你们离开时 我们有交换电话
Yeah. Well, we exchanged numbers when you guys split.
-你都没打来 -对
- You never called. - No. Yeah.
抱歉，情况一直很危险
I'm sorry. It's been, it's been dangerous, you know.
-真的很危险 -没关系
- Real dangerous. - It's okay.
听着，罗杰 这些话我虽然说过
L.J., listen. I know I've said this before...
但是我想我们终于找到了 可以终结一切的证据
...we've found something that'll finally put this stuff behind us.
等尘埃落定 安全的时候我会去接你
When it's good, when it's safe, I'm gonna come and get you.
-你、我和你叔叔可以K -爸
- You, me, your uncle, we can... - Dad.
-什么事？ -我真的很希望你终结这一切
- Yeah? - I want you to end this more than anything,
可是我回学校了
But I'm in school again.
用的是假名 可是还是上学，你懂吗？
Under a fake name, but it's still school, you know?
虽然不一样
I mean, it's not the same,,,
但这是我这么久以来 最接近家的感受
,,, but it's the closest thing to a home I've had in a long time,
我的意思K我只是说K
I guess... I guess I'm just saying,,,
现在，这一阵子
,,, that for now, for a while,,,
我只想留在同一个地方
...I just wanna stay in one place.
过正常的生活
Have something normal,
好，我了解
Yeah, yeah. I get it.
我K
I,,,,
-我要找珍说话 -好
- I need to speak with Jane. - Okay,
我爱你，爸
I love you, Dad.
我也爱你，孩子
I love you too, son.
（阿拉巴马州，伯明罕）
韦伯斯特先生，抱歉让你久等
Mr. Webster, sorry to keep you waiting.
没关系，医生
Oh, it's no problem, doc.
我只想说我很感激你
I just wanted to tell you how much I appreciate you...
这么快就能见我
...seeing me on such short notice.
这是当医生的责任
That's what I'm here for.
很好
Good.
因为我有些事想一吐为快
Because I got a few things I need to get off my chest.
再见，珍
See you, Jane.
库柏葛林？
Cooper Green?
前任副检查总长
Former deputy attorney general.
他在华府、芝加哥、纽约间行动
Splits his time between D.C., Chicago and New York.
珍说他是爸 长久以来的照应人
Jane says he's been an ally of Dad's forever.
找到他，我们就有机会
We find him, we got a shot.
罗杰好吗？
How's L. J?
他还不错
He's all right.
（库柏葛林 （312）555-0124）
库柏葛林办公室你好
Cooper Green's office.
-抱歉，葛林先生现在没空 -拜托，我有重要的事
- Sorry, Mr. Green isn't available at this time. - Please, this is very important,
告诉他 我有艾度柏劳儿子的消息
Just tell him I have some information regarding the sons of Aldo Burrows.
-艾度柏劳？ -对
- Aldo Burrows? - Yes,
他曾经和葛林先生共事过
He and Mr. Green used to work together.
请稍等，我帮你找他
Please hold. I'll try to reach him.
她在找他
She's tracking him down.
-你好 -葛林先生，我是迈克斯科菲尔德
- Hello, - Mr. Green, this is Michael scofield.
知道我是谁吗？
Do you know who I am?
当然，我认识你父亲 我也知道他遇害了
Of course. I knew your father, and I know what happened to him.
我很遗憾，他是个正直的好人
I'm sorry. He was a good man trying to do good things.
我们也是
Well, so are we.
我们手上有个东西
We have something.
-录音？ -你知道这件事？
- The tape? - You've heard of it?
我知道很多人在找这段录音
Well, I know a lot of people have been looking for it.
内容是什么？
What's on the tape?
如果你想知道 伊伯公园西南方
If you want to find out, there is a bronze statue of a mammoth...
有座毛象的铜像
...at the southwest corner of Ebert Park.
请你一小时后过去
I need you there in an hour.
-你有蓝色西装吗？ -有
- Do you have a blue suit? - Yes,
穿上，配上红色领带
Wear it, and a red tie.
这样我们就认得你
That way, we'll know who you are.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
好了
Yeah.
祝你们好运
Good luck.
-会成功的 -是吗？
- This'll work. - You think?
（弗兰克丹奎迪，1945年 3月7日至2005年6月1日）
你好，莎拉
Hello, sara.
我就知道 你总有一天会出现
I figured you'd show up eventually.
你看起来不错，布鲁斯
You look good, Bruce.
我父亲的死 让你过得不错
You've done well for yourself at my father's expense.
你父亲的死和我无关 他是被谋杀的
I had nothing to do with your father. He was murdered.
是你杀的，之后又想谋杀我 少在那里装K
By you, and then you tried to have me killed. Don't...
你怎能这么说？
How can you say that?
我的电话遭窃听 他们听到你说你在公共电话旁
My line was tapped, they heard you tell me that you were at that payphone.
-莎拉，我和你家人交情匪浅 -所以你的背叛更令人作恶
- Sara, I've known your family my entire life. - Which makes your betrayal disgusting.
告诉你，我已经被折磨过 没有用的
For what it's worth, I've been tortured already. Didn't work.
我没必要向你证明我的清白
I shouldn't have to defend myself to you.
如果你不信任我 我也只能祝你好运
If you can't trust me, then all I can do is just wish you luck.
你走啊
Go.
在你开口前 我替你先节省时间，老大
Look, before you get started, I'm gonna save you some time here, jefe,
我之前为你通风报信 应该就此打住
I played rat for you once, and that was it.
现在有人替我撑腰了
I got protection now.
我让这里的头目挑选衣服 干净的床单、新短裤
I let the top bangers in here cherry-pick the laundry, clean sheets, new shorts.
所以没人碰得了我
And for that, I'm untouchable.
要怎么威胁随便你
So threaten all you want, homes.
老兄，你想干嘛？
Yo, man, what are you gonna do?
看来你不常打网球，曼杰
You don't look like you play too much tennis, Manche.
这应该比较适合你的调调
This is probably more your speed.
娱乐器材柜
Entertainment center.
宽荧幕电浆电视
Wide-screen plasma.
弹珠台、撞球台
Pinball. Pool table.
-这是什么？ -你的未来
- What the hell is this? - Your future.
肯卡基低保安矫正中心
At Kankakee Minimum security Correctional Center...
那里的狱警比枕头还柔软
...where the only thing softer than the pillows are the guards.
我不是来威胁你
I didn't come here to threaten.
何苦鞭打一只骡
I mean, why whip the mule...
要是给他方糖吃 他就会更努力工作？
...when he'll work even harder for a sugar cube?
这个后台这么快 就把我救出这监狱
The same connections got this fox out of the river so quick.
我想你也可以靠一下
Well, I can use them for you too.
我只想知道你表哥苏克 打算逃到墨西哥哪个地方
All I need to know is where down in Mejico your cousin sucre is headed.
（墨西哥，里约华雷兹）
宝贝，快看
Look, mami, look.
我就说有骆马吧
I told you. Llamas.
这应该是羊鸵吧
I think those are alpacas.
我说是一群骆马
That's what I said. A pack of Ilamas.
费南多K
Fernando! Fernando!
（阿姨？）
（我姐姐的宝贝儿子）
（很高兴见到你）
（这位是犸丽）
（这是我们的孩子）
（我们在这很安全吧？）
（对，这里现在是你们的家）
我想说的是，医生
What I'm trying to tell you, doc...
我这一生感觉都像是 铁轨上的硬币
...is I just feel like I've been a penny on the train tracks my entire life.
那台老火车每天都会经过
And that old Union Pacific just keeps on coming every day.
来来回回压过我，辗过我 但我就是压不平
Back and forth, just running me down, running me over, but I will not flatten.
就是压不平
I will not flatten.
你知道硬币的优点是什么吗 韦伯斯特先生？
You know the nice things about pennies, Mr. Webster?
硬币上有年份
They have dates on them.
你可以选年份，自己的年份
And you can pick the date. Your own date.
今天的年份
Today's date.
你可以重新开始
You can get a fresh start.
你可以当个崭新的硬币
You can be a brand-new shiny penny.
医生，我得老实说 我今天进来的时候
You know, I gotta be honest with you, doc. I had no intention of, whatsoever...
我根本不打算和你聊
...talking to you once I got inside your office today.
但我得承认，心理治疗真的K
But I have to admit, I find therapy...
很有疗效
Well, it's therapeutic.
我不太懂
I don't follow.
如果你今天不打算跟我聊 为何来找我？
If you didn't plan on talking today, why did you come in?
我今天在公车站的后面 看到广告
Well, I saw that ad on the back of the bus stop today...
虽然我俩并非 一个模子刻出来的
...and though it wasn't exactly like looking in the mirror...
但不能否认 我们的脸的确有些相似
...you can't deny that there's a certain commonality in our visages.
我想我们的确有点像
I guess we do look a little bit alike.
可是我还是不懂
But I don't understand.
你K要干嘛？
What...? What the hell you think you're doing?
-你好 -葛林先生？
- Hello. - Mr, Green?
-是 -我是林克柏劳
- Yes. - This is Lincoln Burrows.
照我的话去做
Do exactly what I say.
把你的西装外套 丢进身后的垃圾筒
Your suit jacket. Toss it in the trash behind you.
-什么？ -快点
- Excuse me? - Do it.
好，价值两千元的西装 已经丢进垃圾筒了
All right, I just threw my $2000 Zegna suit jacket in the garbage.
很好
Good,
公园另一头有个喷水池 四分钟后过去
There's a fountain on the other side of the park. Be there in four minutes.
四K？
Four...?
长话短说，手机快没电了
Make it quick. The cell is running out of juice.
你猜对了
You were right.
-有人跟踪他？ -对
- He's being tailed? - Yeah,
交给我去办
on it.
-什么事？ -我找一个穿西装的人
- Yeah? - I'm looking for a guy in a suit,
很多人都穿西装K
Lot of guys with suits...
是我
It's me.
看见喷水池了吗？
See the fountain?
-怎么会看不见？ -跳进去
- How could I not? - Get in,
他们想弄湿麦克风 以防我们给他装窃听器
They wanna drown the mics, in case we bugged him.
先生，这是给你的
Hey, mister. This is for you.
-我没兴趣 -不是要卖给你
- I'm not interested. - I'm not selling it.
有人给我20元叫我拿给 一个全身落汤鸡的人，拿去
Some dude gave me 20 bucks to give it to the first wet guy I see. Here.
有看到对面的大楼吗？
See the building across from you?
-有 -进去
- Yeah. - Go inside,
太荒谬了，我已经什么都照做了
This is getting ridiculous. I've done everything you asked.
-如果你们想见我K -我们被骗太多次了
- Lf you wanna meet me... - Been burned way too many times.
我们要确保 这次不会出差错
We need to make sure this thing goes down right.
进去，手机继续贴住耳朵
Go inside, and keep the phone to your ear.
-是？ -情况如何？
- Yeah? - Where are we?
他们进了贝克博物馆 但有我们的人
They've gone inside the Beck Museum, But we got men out back,
他逃不掉的
He's not going anywhere.
-说 -去伊伯公园
- Yeah? - Get to Ebert Park,
我有人手在跟踪 斯科菲尔德和柏劳
I have men on Scofield and Burrows,
伊伯公园？
Ebert Park?
斯科菲尔德打算和 我们监视的目标见面
Scofield set a meet with a target we're surveilling.
斯科菲尔德怎么会在芝加哥？
What the hell's scofield doing in Chicago?
猎物自己送上门 你还有疑问？
You're asking why the deer walked into your cross hairs?
抓住机会，曼宏
Just take the shot, Mahone.
我会处理K
I'm on it, I'm on it.
还有亚历
And, Alex,
富兰克林
Franklin.
-我用他帮我抓斯科菲尔德 -对
- I'm using Franklin to help me find scofield. - Yeah,
但我们不需要他了
We don't need him for that anymore,
我需要的是他 死得不会启人疑窦
What I do need is a death with no questions.
听着，还没有消息 但我肯定他很快会回应，好吗？
Hey, look, it's nothing yet, man, but I'm sure he'll hit me real soon, okay?
如果我遇到和你同样的遭遇
You know, if I were in your situation...
你做的一切，所有的决定
...everything you've done, every decision you've made...
我也会如出一辙
...I'd have done the same thing.
你是个好人，好父亲
You're a good man, a good father.
我们的计划有点改变
There's been a change of plans.
看来我不需要你帮忙了
And it looks like I'm not gonna need your help after all.
你们已经找到斯科菲尔德了
So you found scofield.
我的同事就快逮到他了
My colleagues are getting pretty close, yeah.
-所以K -所以你可以放我走了
- So... - so I guess you can set me free, then.
当然不行
Of course not.
-我们之间有协议，对吧？ -对
- You and me, we had a deal, right? - Right.
我让你老婆出狱，医治你的女儿
I get your wife released, take care of your daughter's health...
你帮我找到斯科菲尔德
...and you get me scofield.
可是你已经找到他了 你刚刚才说的
But you're getting him yourself. You just said that.
我知道，我只想告诉你
I know, I know. I just want you to know...
我会遵守协议，帮助你的家人
...that I'm gonna keep my promise to you, and I'm gonna help your family.
但我也需要你帮忙
But I'm gonna need your help too.
这件事你一定不想做
And this is something you're not gonna wanna do.
我也不想要你这样 但我需要你做
I don't want you to do this, but I need you to.
如果你拒绝，我会再逮捕凯西
If you don't, I'll have Kacee arrested again...
停止蒂蒂的医疗
...and I'll have Dede's medical care stopped...
我会怨自己、痛恨自己
...and I will hate myself, and it'll make me sick...
但我发誓
...but I swear to God...
我会毁了她们的人生 所以不要逼我
I will ruin their lives. Don't make me.
你到底想说什么？
What the hell are you saying to me?
待会你的牢房里会有个包裹
Later, you'll get a package in your cell.
是我给你的 我要你使用，懂吗？
It's gonna be from me. I need you to use it, okay?
里面是什么？
Well, what's in it?
等等，里面到底有什么？
Yo. Yo, what the hell is in it, man?
使用它，不然你会后悔
Just use it or you'll wish you had.
包裹里有什么？
What's in the package?
包裹里到底有什么？
What the hell is in the package, man?
等等，包裹里有什么东西？
Yo, what the hell is in the package, man?
我到大厅了
Okay, I'm in the lobby.
走上左边的楼梯
Take the stairs to your left.
上去之后，穿过天桥
When you get to the top, cross the catwalk,
我走过来了
okay, I'm across.
往走廊走，下楼到地下室
Go down the hall, down the stairs to the basement.
进去白色的门
Go through the white door.
左边的门
The one on the left,
莎拉，你早该先来找我
sara, I wish you'd come to me first.
我和库柏葛林很熟
Cooper Green and I go way back.
现在能帮迈克 和林克的人只有他了
If anyone can help Michael and Lincoln, it's him.
-有事能效劳吗？ -是，葛林先生在吗？
- Can I help you? - Yeah, is Mr. Green in?
他在等你吗？
Is he expecting you?
布鲁斯
Bruce.
太好了，你回来了 我是来帮你的
Oh, good, you're back. I'm here to help you.
-帮我？帮什么？ -斯科菲尔德和柏劳在哪里？
- Help me? With what? - Scofield and Burrows. Where are they now?
-真是太扯了 -葛林先生，这是地下隧道
- This is absurd. - Mr, Green, this tunnel goes underground,
你已经在另一栋大楼下方
You're already under another building,
有看到右边第二扇门吗？
see the second door on your right?
恭喜
Congratulations.
你到达了
You made it.
抱歉，我是莎拉丹奎迪
I'm sorry, sara Tancredi.
你今天应该见过 斯科菲尔德和柏劳吧？
I trust you've met with scofield and Burrows today?
如果有，我应该会记得
Well, I'm sure I'd remember if I did.
莎拉？
Sara?
如果你是库柏葛林 迈克现在见的人是谁？
If you're Cooper Green, who's with Michael right now?
葛林先生？
Mr. Green?
我是迈克斯科菲尔德
I'm Michael scofield.
很高兴终于见到你
Well, it's nice to finally meet you.
录音在你手上吗？
Do you have the tape?
就在这
It's right here.
-什么事？ -林克，是我莎拉，听我说
- Yeah? - Lincoln, it's Sara, Listen to me,
和迈克见面的人不是库柏葛林 你有听见吗？
The man Michael's with is not Cooper Green. You hear me?
现在和迈克见面的人 不是库柏葛林
The man that Michael's with right now is not Cooper Green.
动作要快，这里是芝加哥
We should hurry. We're in Chicago.
公司很快就会察觉你来了
Won't be long before the Company knows you're in town.
我们要去哪里？
Where are we going?
我们要确保 录音交到对的人手上
Well, we're gonna make sure that that tape goes into the right hands.
谁的手上？
Whose?
一个朋友
A friend.
什么样的朋友？
What kind of friend?
他是联邦法官
He's a federal judge.
这样你满意吗？
Is that good enough for you?
这段录音是我哥和我的人生
Well, this tape is my brother's life and mine.
因此，我要知道名字
And consequently, I need a name.
史考特华伦法官
Judge scott Warren.
他是前总统米尔斯
A lifetime appointee...
指派的终生制法官
...who was put on the bench by President Mills.
他不怕丢掉工作 也无须效忠雷诺兹
He has no job to lose, no loyalty to Reynolds.
他和我们一样希望她下台
Wants to see her gone, just like us.
我们走吧，我的车停在铜像附近
Well, let's go. I left my car over by the statue.
你被人跟踪，葛林先生
You were tailed, Mr. Green.
由法官来找我们
The judge comes to us.
我会安排会面时间
I'll set up the meeting.
你有看见我的衣服吗？
Do you see my clothes?
你哥已经确保 甩掉了所有跟踪我的人
Your brother made certain that anybody who was tailing me is long gone.
更重要的是，我有气喘
And on top of that, I'm an asthmatic.
我的吸入器在外套口袋里 林克逼我把外套扔了
My inhaler is in my jacket pocket, which Lincoln made me throw away.
我现在没事 但十分钟后我会呼吸困难
I'm okay now, but in about 10 minutes, I'm gonna have a hard time breathing.
车上手套箱有备用吸入器 所以可以回我车上了吗？
I've got a spare in my glove box, so could we please just get back to my car?
我的车就在几条街外
My car is just a few blocks away.
-沙丁胺醇、寇多赛还是沛德松？ -什么？
- Albuterol, Cortizaide or prednizone? - What?
我母亲也有气喘
My mother was an asthmatic.
-你的吸入器里是什么药？ -这有什么差别吗？
- What do you use in your inhaler? - What the hell difference does it make?
请你回答问题
Just answer the question, please.
你真的很烦人，你知道吗？
You're a real piece of work, you know that?
我到底要向你证明几次？
How many times I gotta prove myself to you?
就这一次
Just one.
好吧，寇多赛
Fine. Cortizaide.
抱歉，我K
I'm sorry, it's just...
如果你能了解K
If you knew what...
了解我们经历的一切
If you knew what we'd been through.
我了解
I understand.
-可以回我车上了吧？ -好
- Can we now just please go to my car? - Yeah.
一张到曼谷的单程机票，谢谢
A one-way ticket to Bangkok, s'il vous plait,
很抱歉
oh, I'm sorry.
（伯明罕，阿拉巴马州 伯明罕国际机场）
We don't have anything until tomorrow. Unless you don't mind...
明天才有机位 还是你不介意
到芝加哥转机？
...taking a few connections through Chicago?
到国外还要再转机一次
And there's one more international stop.
能先出发就好
Whatever leaves first.
好，麻烦你出示证件
Okay. ID, please.
是史戴摩先生？
Okay, Mr. Stammel?
是史戴摩医生
Oh, it's Dr. Stammel.
-谢谢你 -好，请稍等一下
- And thank you. - All right. It'll be just a few minutes.
-我帮你托运行李 -不，我要随身带着
- I'll check this bag for you. - Oh, no. It's coming with me.
先生，那已经远远超过 随身行李的重量限制
Sir, I know that bag is way over the weight limit for carryon.
三顿重的飞机在天上飞 多几磅又有何差别K
What difference does a few pounds make on a 3-ton aircraft whether it's up above...?
这会违反联邦航空总署规定
It's an FAA violation.
先生，你的行李会很安全的
Sir, your bag will be safe.
今天风城的旅客 将有苦头吃了
Today will be a tough day for travelers in the Windy city,,,
因为卡莱尔大饭店 方圆六街区的路
,,, as all streets in a six-block radius of the Grand carlisle Hotel,,,
都已经被封锁，为的是
,,, have been closed to traffic in anticipation,,,
雷诺兹总统今晚将在 该饭店发表演说
,,, of President Reynolds' speech there this evening,
这是总统到 中西部访问的其中一站
This will be one of several Midwestern stops for the president,,,
她正开始启动竞选的造势活动
,,, as she ramps up her election campaign,
西奥，我知道你是新来的 但笔记纸两面都要用，懂吗？
Hey, Theo, I know you're new, but we use both sides of legal pads in this office, okay?
回收前，要先降低使用量
Before we recycle, we reduce.
卡曼其人善用整只水牛
The Comanche used the entire buffalo.
我们也要效法
So can we.
事实上 多数的族人会在农田耕作
Actually, majority of tribes would farm land...
直到土壤不再肥沃，他们就会E离
...till it was stripped of its fertility, then they'd just move on.
印度安人会保护资源 是自由主义白人内疚的迷思
The Indian as conservationist is a myth created by white liberal guilt.
-保罗 -你好，克莉丝汀
- Paul. - Hi, Kristine.
我以为在爸的葬礼上可以见到你
I'd hoped maybe I'd see you at Dad's funeral.
那个人在心跳停止前早就死了
That man died long before his heart stopped.
葬礼只是个形式罢了
That funeral was a formality.
-这么说不公平 -是实话
- That's really not fair. - It's true.
你想知道妈的近况吗？
So you wanna know how Mom is?
有人把你从胯间生出来 不代表她就是你母亲
Someone spitting you out of their crotch doesn't make them your mother.
那女人是疯子
That woman is insane.
你不记得？你都压抑在心里吗？
Do you remember? Have you suppressed it all?
我知道，保罗 我每天都要面对她，和你不一样
I know, Paul. I was there every day, unlike you.
-我面对她18年了 -然后你一声不响地离开
- I was there for 18 years. - And then you just left.
我才10岁，保罗
I was 10, Paul.
你是我唯一的家人，你却丢下我
You were all I had in the world, and you just left me there.
对不起
I'm sorry.
如果我有办法，我一定会带你走 而且我每天都想你
If I could've taken you with me, I would've, and I've thought about you every day.
我已经不是你记忆中的哥哥
I'm not the brother you remember.
我变了
I've changed...
变得K非常糟糕
...in a really bad way.
现在我已经分不清善恶了
To the point where I don't know what good or bad is anymore.
我要去做一件事 我非这么做不可
And I am gonna do something, I have to do something...
很多人将会认为我罪不可赦
...that a lot of people are gonna think is horrible.
-保罗 -我只要你记住
- Paul. - And you just remember...
和你一同长大的哥哥
...the brother you grew up with.
别忘了他
Just remember him.
你是我的妹妹，克莉丝汀，我爱你
You're my sister, Kristine. I love you.
我被打晕 我不知道他们往哪逃走
I was out cold. I don't know where they went.
是他们要你 在芝加哥市中心见面？
And it was their idea for you to meet them here in the middle of Chicago?
对
Yeah.
真是的
Oh, man.
-曼宏？ -你太慢通知我，他们逃走了
- Mahone? - You brought me in too late. They're gone.
-那就去找他们 -我想搞清楚
- Then find them. - Let me get this straight.
这两兄弟回到 离逃出的监狱15里外的城市
They come back to a city 15 miles from the prison they escaped from.
他们为何要这样？
Why would they do that?
也许因为总统要在芝加哥演说 他们另有计谋
Maybe because the president's in Chicago to make a speech, they're up to something.
所以我们要把他们揪出来
Which is why we need to find them.
有这么多人
And of all people...
他们却要见 检察总长办公室的人
...they wanna meet somebody from the attorney general's office.
重点是什么？
Your point?
柏劳是清白的
Burrows is innocent.
你真厉害，亚历 跟广告说的一样
You're good, Alex, as advertised.
没有人是真正清白的
No one's truly innocent.
这点你应该最清楚
You, of all people, should know that,
一定是接待员搞的鬼 我只和她说过话
It must've been the receptionist. She's the only one I spoke to.
迈克斯科菲尔德，这位是库柏葛林
Michael scofield, Cooper Green.
我们得在宝宝来之前 尽量找机会做
We gotta get as much of that in as possible before the baby gets here.
为什么？
Why?
因为K
Because.
等宝宝越长越大 这样不是很怪吗？
Once the baby's growing in there, doesn't it just get kind of wrong?
也对
Oh, yeah.
-干嘛？ -我感觉到宝宝在动
- What? - I just felt the baby move.
-费南多，不可能的 -我很清楚感觉到了
- No, Fernando, that's impossible. - I know what I just felt.
医生说在某些行为后
Well, the doctor did say that he can become active...
他会变得比较好动
...after certain activities.
-你有感觉到吗？ -有，轻轻的震动
- Did you feel that? - Yeah, like a flutter?
震动才怪，他真强壮
Flutter, my ass. He's strong.
他要当国家足球队的队长
He's gonna be the captain of the national soccer team.
你有听到吗，小子？
You hear that, junior?
等你一出生 我就要给你一颗足球
Soon as you're born, I'm putting a soccer ball in your hands.
不行，要给他书本
No, he's gonna have books.
好吧
Fine.
足球的书
Books about soccer.
宝贝
Hey, baby.
我就说一切都会事过境E
I told you everything was gonna work out.
我们在荒凉的无人之处
We're out in the middle of nowhere.
宝宝又健康
The baby's doing great.
一切都会很美好
Everything's gonna be perfect.
各位乘客请注意
Your attention, please,
看来天候状况一切良好
It looks like we've got nothing but smooth skies ahead,,,
我们很快就能抵达墨西哥
,,, so we should be arriving in Mejico,,,,
抱歉，餐点什么时候上？ 我快饿死了
Excuse me, when is the meal coming? I'm starved.
为了降低机票价钱
As a way to keep ticket prices low...
我们的服务项目 已不包括机上餐点
...we removed in-flight meals from our service package.
那服务项目剩下什么？
Well, what's left on the service package?
脆饼和麦片
Pretzels and bags of Krispity Krunch.
给我脆饼
Pretzels.
请稍等
Just a few minutes.
有空请帮我倒饮料，亲爱的
Freshen me up when you get a chance, darling.
马上来，史戴摩医生
Right away, Dr. Stammel.
蒂蒂的状况很好
Dede's doing real good.
对药物有反应，也有进食
Responding to the meds, eating.
她不会有事的
She's gonna be okay.
都是因为你
Because of you.
-是你救了她一命 -好
- She's gonna be okay because of you. - Yeah.
我必须知道
I need to know...
你愿意原谅我
...you know, that you forgive me.
我知道，我当然原谅你
I know that. Of course I forgive you.
蒂蒂四岁的时候 她想看一卷录影带
You know, when Dede was like 4, she wanted to watch this video.
我一直跟她说，比赛转播完再看
And I kept telling her, you know, after the game.
比赛完再看好吗？
After the game, okay?
她一直不断地吵 我失去耐心，于是我骂了她
She kept asking and kept asking. I lost my patience and I snapped at her.
我狠狠对她大吼
I snapped at her real bad.
之后她走到角落
Well, she went over into the corner...
我甚至没有过去安慰她
...and I didn't even go over and say anything.
这么久以前的事
Why are you getting yourself upset...
你为何还拿来烦心？ 宝贝，这么久了，蒂蒂爱你
...over something that happened years ago, baby, years ago? Dede loves you.
我要你替我做件事 我要你告诉她我很抱歉
I want you to do something for me. I want you to tell her that I'm sorry.
我真的很抱歉 我的小女儿是我的一切
I'm so sorry. And that my baby girl means everything to me.
我要你告诉她 她是我的一切，好吗？
I want you to tell her that she means everything to me, okay?
每天都要告诉她
You tell her that every day.
-时间到了 -无论如何
- Time. - No matter what.
-女士 -告诉她
- Ma'am. - Tell her.
告诉她，好吗？ 不管发生什么事我都爱她
Tell her, okay? No matter what, he loves her, okay?
-女士 -拜托，一定要告诉她
- Ma'am. - Please. Please, you gotta tell her.
-一定要告诉她K -好K
- You have to tell her... - okay, okay, okay.
-女士，你得离开了 -告诉她爸爸爱她
- Ma'am, you really have to go. - Tell her that her daddy loves her.
请注意K
Attention, attention.
所有群众全程不得越过护栏
All spectators must remain behind the barricade at all times.
往南半条街上有炸弹客 组长要你去处理
We got a Boom Charlie half a block south. Team leader wants you there.
-是什么手法？ -是及时爆炸装置绑在K
- What's the M. O? - He's got an I.E.D. Strapped to...
他指定要你到这座喷水池？
He asked you to come to this fountain specifically?
对
Yeah.
公园地图借我看一下
Let me take a look at that park map.
为何不去公园东边的喷水池？
Why not the fountain on the east side of the park?
因为这座离公共电话比较近
Because this was closer to the payphone they called me at.
不，因为这座离他们比较近
No, because this one's closer to them.
他们要你去铜像见面 然后到喷水池
They tell you to meet them at the statue, then the fountain...
然后要你去公园对面的大楼
...then they send you to the building across the park.
为什么？
Why?
因为他们要让你 保持在视线范围内
Because they wanna keep you in their sights.
因为他们在监视你
Because they're watching you.
可是在哪里？ 铜像、喷水池、大楼
But from where? The statue, fountain, building.
那里，那间饭店
There. The hotel.
你知道它的份量吗？
You know what you have?
-我想我们很清楚 -你在干嘛？
- I think we have a pretty good idea. - What you doing?
寻找随身碟的独特资料 才能将它和其他随身碟区分
Getting unique data from the memory key so we can identify this key from any other...
再做标示 开始做证物管制链的纪录
...label it, start a proper record of the chain of custody...
好呈报给我信任的法官
...to present to the judges I trust.
好
Cool.
-可恶 -怎么了？
- No. - What's wrong?
是随身碟上的日期戳记
No, it's the date stamp on the memory key.
这是复制的时间
It's the copy date.
-抱歉，什么意思？ -这是档案复制的时间
- I'm sorry, what's that? - It's the date the damn thing was copied.
不是对话录音当时的日期
Not the date that the conversation was originally recorded.
那又如何？ 你自己也听过内容了
So what? I mean, you heard what was on the tape.
没有对话发生时机的 正确日期戳记
Without a time stamp of exactly when this conversation took place...
我们无法证明这段 戴伦斯史泰门的对话
...we can't prove that this is Terrence steadman talking...
是在你据称杀了他之后发生
...after you supposedly killed him.
这可能是他丧礼 一年前的谈话内容
This could've happened a year before his funeral.
既然无法鉴定真假
No, it can't be authenticated...
就无法呈堂证供
...so it can't be admitted to any court as evidence.
人们为了录音送命 我的家人因此死了
People died because of this. My family died.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
在法律上来说 这段录音毫无用处
Legally speaking, this tape is useless.
-你好 -亚历山大曼宏，调查局
- Hi. - Alexander Mahone, FBI.
这两人有来住房吗？
Have either of these men checked in?
-我没有见过 -这个女人呢？
- Not that I've seen. - How about this woman?
有
Yeah.
1006房
Room 1006.
1006，谢谢
Ten-o-six. Ten-o-six. Thank you.
还没结束，就差这么一点了
It's not over. We're this close.
你已经说没救了
You've already said it's done.
事实上，我是说无法在法庭上 证明你无罪
Actually, I said it couldn't help exonerate you in a court of law.
它在法外或许还有帮助
Maybe it can help you outside the law.
怎么帮？
How?
我们都听过这段对话
Well, we all heard the conversation.
录音不只能证明林克的清白
There's more to this tape than potential proof of Lincoln's innocence.
更能证明卡洛琳雷诺兹的罪行
There is proof of Caroline Reynolds' guilt.
一个她不想让 任何人知道的罪行
Guilt about something she does not want anyone to know anything about.
所以我们要勒索她
So we blackmail her.
我是法务人员，不是我说的
I'm an officer of the court. I didn't say that.
勒索换取什么？
Blackmail in exchange for what?
总统大赦
A presidential pardon.
陷害我的女人 现在要她还我自由
So the woman that set me up is gonna set me free.
我认为她会亲自签字同意
I think she'll sign it with her own hand.
A、B小队，这里是1号队长
Ace Team, Beta Team, this is Leader One,
所有群众请勿跨越护栏
All spectators must remain behind the barricade.
总统即将抵达
The president will be arriving shortly.
总统将在两分钟内抵达基地
The president will reach Home Base in T-minus 2 minutes,
我爱你
I love you.